PowerPMPPool={"Questions":[{"Question":"You plan to hold a series of meeting as you execute the project plan. While different attendees will attend each  meeting, a best practice to follow is to:","R1":"Group stakeholders into categories to determine which","R2":"Not mix the types of meetings on your project","R3":"Be sensitive to the fact that stakeholders often have very different objectives and invite them to determine  the meeting’s agenda","R4":"Recognize that roles and responsibilities may overlap so focus on holding meetings primarily for  decision making ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You have assembled a core team to develop the project management plan for the next generation of fatigue fighting drugs. The science is complex, and the extended team  of researchers, clinicians, and patients for trials exceeds  500 people. The content of your project management plan  will be directed primarily by two factors. They are—","R1":"Project complexity and the capability of resources","R2":"Number of resources and project schedule","R3":"Team member experience and budget","R4":"Application area and complexity ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"When you established the change control board for your avionics project, you established specific procedures to  govern its operation. The procedures require all approved  changes to baselines to be reflected in the—","R1":"Performance measurement baseline","R2":"Change management plan","R3":"Quality assurance plan","R4":"Project management plan ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The purpose of economic value added (EVA) is to—","R1":"Determine the opportunity costs associated with","R2":"Determine a non–time-dependent measure of profit or return","R3":"Assess the net operating profit after taxes","R4":"Evaluate the return on capital percent versus the cost of capital percent ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Facilitation techniques are used throughout project management. Your company is embarking on a project to completely eliminate defects in its products. You are the  project manager for this project, and you are developing  your project charter. To assist you, which of the following  facilitation techniques did you use?","R1":"Surveys","R2":"Delphi approach","R3":"Meeting management","R4":"Focus groups ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The direct and manage project work process truly is important in project management. It affects many other  key processes and uses inputs from others. Working with  your team at its kickoff meeting, you explain the key  benefit of this process is to—","R1":"Implement approved changes","R2":"Provide overall management of the project work","R3":"Lead and perform activities in the project management plan","R4":"Perform activities to accomplish project objectives ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You are fairly new to managing a project but have been a team member for many years. You are pleased you  were selected to manage your company’s 2015 model line  of hybrid vehicles. You are now planning your project  and have been preparing the subsidiary plans as well.  You realize some project documents also are required to  help manage your project. An example of one that you  believe will be especial helpful is the—","R1":"Business case","R2":"Key performance indicators","R3":"Project management information system","R4":"Project statement of work ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You realize that projects represent change, and on your projects, you always seem to have a number of change  requests to consider. In your current project to manage  the safety of the nation’s cheese products and the testing  methods used, you decided to prepare a formal change  management plan. An often overlooked type of change  request is—","R1":"Adding new subject matter experts to your team","R2":"Updates","R3":"Work performance information","R4":"Enhancing the reviews performed by your project’s governance board ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You have been directed to establish a change   control system for your company, but must convince your  colleagues to use it. To be effective, the change control  system must include—","R1":"Procedures that define how project documents may","R2":"Specific change requests expected on the project and plans to respond to each one","R3":"Performance reports that forecast project changes","R4":"A description of the functional and physical characteristics of an item or system ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"You are working on the next generation of software for mobile phones for your telecommunications company.  While time to market is critical, you know from your  work on other projects that management reviews can be  helpful and plan to use them on your project. You are  documenting them as part of your—","R1":"Governance plan","R2":"Change management plan","R3":"Performance reviews","R4":"Project management plan ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You are project manager for a systems integration effort and need to procure the hardware components from  external sources. Your subcontracts administrator has told  you to prepare a product description, which is referenced  in a—","R1":"Project statement of work","R2":"Contract scope statement","R3":"Request for proposal","R4":"Contract ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Because your project is slated to last five years, you believe rolling wave planning is appropriate. It provides  information about the work to be done—","R1":"Throughout all project phases","R2":"For successful completion of the current project phase","R3":"For successful completion of the current and subsequent project phases","R4":"In the next project phase ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"You are managing a project to introduce a new product to the marketplace that is expected to have a very long life.  In this situation, the concept of being temporary,which is  part of the definition of a project,—","R1":"Does not apply because the project will have a","R2":"Does not apply to the product to be created","R3":"Recognizes that the project team will outlive the actual project","R4":"Does not apply because the project will not be short in duration ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"When closing a project, it is a best practice to—","R1":"Update the project documents","R2":"Prepare a sustainment plan for the project’s benefits","R3":"Measure product scope against the project management plan","R4":"Review the scope baseline ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You are responsible for a project management training curriculum that is offered throughout the organization.  In this situation, your intangible deliverables are—","R1":"Employees who can apply the training effectively","R2":"Training materials for each course","R3":"Certificates of completion for everyone who completes the program","R4":"The training curriculum as advertised in your catalog ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Working on your project management training curricula project, you decided it would be beneficial to you to  become an active member of the Project Management  Institute as part of the objectives of your project is  to ensure it is aligned with PMI was requesting volunteers to  participate in development of a similar standard on the  Scope Statement. You volunteered, and now the Standard  is issued. This is an example of:","R1":"Improving your own competency as a project manager","R2":"Corrective action","R3":"Preventive action","R4":"A requirement for you to immediately update your project management plan ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Project management processes describe project work, while product-oriented management processes specify  the project’s product. Therefore, a project management  process and a product-oriented management process—","R1":"Overlap and interact throughout the project","R2":"Are defined by the project life cycle","R3":"Are concerned with describing and organizing project work","R4":"Are similar for each application area ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The close project or phase process addresses actions and activities concerning all of the following EXCEPT—","R1":"Completion or exit criteria for the project or phase","R2":"Stakeholder approval that the project has meet their requirements","R3":"Review of the project and/or phase information for potential future use","R4":"Documentation that completed deliverables have been accepted ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You are a personnel management specialist recently assigned to a project team working on a team-based  reward and recognition system. The other team  members also work in the human resources department.  The project charter should be issued by—","R1":"The project manager","R2":"The client","R3":"A sponsor","R4":"A member of the PMO who has jurisdiction over human resources ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Different types of project phases are used on   projects, and each phase culminates in the completion of at  least one deliverable. The high-level nature of these  phases means they are an element of the project life  cycle. Some phases start before others complete. If this  approach is followed, it may result in—","R1":"An increase in the number of issues","R2":"Increasing the schedule","R3":"The need for a CCB","R4":"More rework ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Assume your company is a leader in the market in production of cereal products. It has been in this  market  for over 50 years. You are the project manager for a  new product that is a derivative from the company’s core  product. As you determine a life cycle for this project,  you believe you should follow one that is—","R1":"Incremental","R2":"Predictive","R3":"Iterative","R4":"Adaptive ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Oftentimes when a project is terminated, senior managers will replace the project manager with an individual who  is skilled in closing out projects. If this is done, the first  step for the termination manager should be to—","R1":"Notify all relevant stakeholders of the termination","R2":"Complete the lessons learned report","R3":"Conduct an immediate review of the work packages","R4":"Review the status of all contracts ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"On your project you want to avoid bureaucracy, so you adopt an informal approach to change control. The main  problem with this approach is—","R1":"There is no \"paper trail\" of change activity","R2":"Regular disagreements between the project manager and the functional manager will occur","R3":"There are misunderstandings regarding what was agreed upon by stakeholders","R4":"There is a lack of sound cost estimating to assess the change’s impact ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"All projects involve some extent of change, because they involve work that is unique in some fashion. Therefore, it  is important that a project management plan includes a—","R1":"Description of the change request process","R2":"Configuration management plan","R3":"Methodology for preventive action to avoid the need for excessive changes","R4":"A work authorization system ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You are examining multiple scope change requests on a project you were asked to take over because the previous  project manager decided to resign. To assess the degree  to which the project scope will change, you need to  compare the requests to which project document?","R1":"Preliminary scope statement","R2":"WBS","R3":"Change management plan","R4":"Scope management plan ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You are managing a complex project for a new method of heating and air conditioning in vehicles. You will use  both solar and wind technologies in this project to reduce  energy costs. Therefore, you must ensure that the work of  your project will result in delivering the project’s specified  scope, which means that you should measure completion  of the product scope against the—","R1":"Scope management plan","R2":"Project management plan","R3":"Product requirements","R4":"Requirements management plan ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Rather than use a WBS, your team developed a bill of materials to define the project’s work components. A  customer review of this document uncovered that a scope  change was needed, because a deliverable had not been  defined, and a change request was written subsequently.  This is an example of a change request that was the  result of—","R1":"An external event","R2":"An error or omission in defining the scope of the product","R3":"A value-adding change","R4":"An error or omission in defining the scope of the project ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"The project scope statement addresses and documents all the following items EXCEPT—","R1":"Project exclusions","R2":"The relationship between the deliverables and the business need","R3":"Product scope description","R4":"Project management methodology (PMM) ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The first step in collecting requirements on any project, large or small, is to—","R1":"Talk with the project stakeholders through interviews","R2":"Review the scope management plan","R3":"Conduct facilitated workshops with stakeholders","R4":"Prepare a requirements document template that you and your team can use throughout the collect requirements process ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Quality function deployment is one approach for collecting requirements. Assume that you have studied the work of numerous quality experts, such as Deming, Juran, and  Crosby, and your organization has a policy that states  the importance of quality as the key constraint of all  project constraints. You and your team have decided to  use  quality function deployment on your new project to  manufacture turbines that use alternative fuels. The first  step you should use is to—","R1":"Determine the voice of the customer","R2":"Build the house of quality","R3":"Address the functional requirements and how best to meet them","R4":"Hold a focus group of prequalified stakeholders ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Change is inevitable on projects. Uncontrolled changes are often referred to as—","R1":"Rework","R2":"Scope creep","R3":"Configuration items","R4":"Emergency changes ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"In scope control it is important to determine the cause of any unacceptable variance relative to the scope baseline.  This can be done through—","R1":"Root cause analysis","R2":"Control charts","R3":"Inspections","R4":"Project performance measurements ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You are leading a project team to identify potential new products for your organization. One idea was rejected by  management because it would not fit with the organization’s core competencies. You need to recommend other  products using management’s guideline as—","R1":"An assumption","R2":"A risk","R3":"A specification","R4":"A technical requirement ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Any step recommended to bring expected future performance in line with the project management plan  is called—","R1":"Performance evaluation","R2":"Corrective action","R3":"Preventive action","R4":"Defect repair ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Modifications may be needed to the WBS and WBS dictionary because of approved change requests, which  shows that—","R1":"Replanning is an output of control scope","R2":"Scope creep is common on projects","R3":"Rebaselining will be necessary","R4":"Variance is relative to the scope baseline ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You and your team are documenting requirements on you project to control fatigue as people need to work more  hours to keep up with the competition. You decided to  set up components for the requirements on your project.  Acceptance criteria are an example of—","R1":"Stakeholder requirements","R2":"Transition requirements","R3":"Project requirements","R4":"Business requirements ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The product scope description is documented as part of the project’s scope statement. It is important to include it  because it—","R1":"Facilitates the project acceptance process","R2":"Describes specific constraints associated with the project","R3":"Progressively elaborates characteristics","R4":"Shows various alternatives considered ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Your company, which operates one of the region’s largest chemical processing plants, has been convicted of  illegally  dumping toxic substances into the local river. The court  has mandated that the required cleanup activities be  completed by February 15. This date is an example of—","R1":"A key event","R2":"A milestone","R3":"A discretionary dependency","R4":"An external dependency ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You are planning to conduct the team-building  portion of your new project management training  curriculum  out-of-doors in the local park. You are limited to   scheduling  the course at certain times of the year, and the best time  for the course to begin is mid-July. One of the more  common date constraints to use as you develop the  project schedule is—","R1":"\"Start no earlier than\"","R2":"\"Finish no earlier than\"","R3":"\"Fixed late start\"","R4":"\"Fixed early finish\" ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Working with your team to provide the basis for measuring and reporting schedule progress, you agree to  use the—","R1":"Schedule management plan","R2":"Network diagram","R3":"Project schedule","R4":"Technical baseline ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Your approved project schedule was based on resource leveling because of a scarcity of resources. Management  has now mandated that the project be completed as soon  as possible. Which of the following methods will you use  to recalculate the schedule?","R1":"Resource manipulation","R2":"Reverse resource allocation","R3":"Critical chain scheduling","R4":"Resource reallocation ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Review the following network diagram and table. Of the various activities, which ones would you crash and in  what order? **** Network Diagram => Activity[Duration](Dependency): A[4](None); B[6](A); C[2](A); D[2](B); E[7](B,C); F[12](C); G[6](D,E,F). *** Table => Activity[Time:Normal][Time:Crash](Cost:Normal)(Cost:Crash)[CrashCostPerWeek]: A[4][2](10,000)(14,000)[2,000];B[6][5](30,000)(42,500)[12,500]; C[2][1](8,000)(9,500)[1,500]; D[2][1](12,000)(18,000)[6,000]; E[7][5](40,000)(52,000)[6,000]; F[12][3](20,000)(29,000)[3,000]; G[6][2](5,000)(30,000)[6,000]; ","R1":"A, C, E, and F","R2":"A, B, D, and F","R3":"A, B, E, and F","R4":"C, A, F, and G ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Decomposition is a technique used for both WBS development and activity definition. Which following statement best describes the role decomposition plays in activity  definition as compared to creating the WBS?","R1":"Final output is described in terms of work packages in","R2":"Final output is described as deliverables or tangible items.","R3":"Final output is described as schedule activities.","R4":"Decomposition is used the same way in scope definition and activity definition. ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Various tools and techniques are available to sequence activities, and several factors can help to determine which  tool or technique to select. When a project manager  decides to include sub-networksor a fragment network as part of his or her scheduling technique, what does this  decision say about the project?","R1":"The work is unique requiring special network diagrams at various stages.","R2":"Software that manages resources is available over an existing electronic network.","R3":"Several identical or nearly identical series of activities are repeated throughout the project.","R4":"Multiple critical paths exist in the project. ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"To meet regulatory requirements, you need to crash your project schedule. Your first step is to compute—","R1":"The cost and time slope for each critical activity that","R2":"The cost of additional resources to be added to the project’s critical path","R3":"The time saved in the overall schedule when tasks are expedited on the critical path","R4":"Three probabilistic time estimates of PERT for each critical path activity ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Project managers should pay attention to   critical and subcritical activities when evaluating project  time performance. One way to do this is to analyze  10 subcritical paths in order of ascending float. This  approach is part of—","R1":"Variance analysis","R2":"Simulation","R3":"Earned value management","R4":"Trend analysis ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Which of the following is a key input to define activities?","R1":"Project management plan","R2":"Project scope management plan","R3":"Schedule management plan","R4":"Project management software ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Several types of float are found in project networks. Float that is used by a particular activity and does NOT affect  the float in later activities is called—","R1":"Extra float","R2":"Free float","R3":"Total float","R4":"Expected float ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"All the following statements regarding critical chain method are true EXCEPT—","R1":"It modifies the schedule to account for limited resources","R2":"The first step is to use conservative estimates for activity  durations","R3":"Duration buffers are added on the critical path","R4":"It focuses on managing buffer activity durations ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You are managing a new technology project designed to improve the removal of hazardous waste from your city.  You are in the planning phase of this project and have  prepared your network diagram. Your next step is to—","R1":"Describe any unusual sequencing in the network","R2":"State the number resources required to complete each activity","R3":"Establish a project calendar and link it to individual resource calendar","R4":"Determine which schedule compression technique is the most appropriate, because your customer requests  that the project be completed as soon as possible ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The risk register may need to be updated as an output of which following process:","R1":"Define activities","R2":"Sequence activities","R3":"Estimate activity resources","R4":"Control schedule ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"The reason that the schedule performance index (SPI) is shown as a ratio is to—","R1":"Enable a detailed analysis of the schedule regardless of","R2":"Distinguish between critical path and noncritical path work packages","R3":"Provide the ability to show performance for a specified time period for trend analysis","R4":"Measure the actual time to complete the project ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"As of the fourth month on the Acme project, cumulative planned expenditures were $100,000. Actual expenditures  totaled $120,000. How is the Acme project doing?","R1":"It is ahead of schedule.","R2":"It is in trouble because of a cost overrun.","R3":"It will finish within the original budget.","R4":"The information is insufficient to make an assessment. ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Your approved cost baseline has changed because of a major scope change on your project. Your next step  should be to—","R1":"Estimate the magnitude of the scope change","R2":"Issue a change request","R3":"Document lessons learned","R4":"Execute the approved scope change ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Which of the following is a tool for analyzing a design, determining its functions, and assessing how to provide  those functions’ cost effectively?","R1":"Pareto diagram","R2":"Value analysis","R3":"Configuration management","R4":"Value engineering ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The cumulative CPI has been shown to be relatively stable after what percentage of project completion?","R1":"5% to 10%","R2":"15% to 20%","R3":"25% to 35%","R4":"50% to 75% ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"The undistributed budget is part of the—","R1":"Management reserve","R2":"Performance measurement baseline","R3":"Level-of-effort cost accounts","R4":"General and administrative accounts ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"There are a number of different earned value management rules of performance measurement that can be established as part of the cost management plan. Which  one of the following is NOT an example of such a rule?","R1":"Code of accounts allocation provision","R2":"Formulas to determine the ETC","R3":"Earned value credit criteria","R4":"Definition of the WBS level ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Which of the following calculations CANNOT be used to determine EAC?","R1":"EV to date plus the remaining project budget","R2":"Accepts actual costs and predicts future ETC work will be done at the budgeted rate","R3":"Assumes what the program has experienced can be expected to continue","R4":"ETC will be performed at an efficiency rate considering both the CPI and SPI ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Typically, the statement \"no one likes to estimate, because they know their estimate will be proven incorrect\" is true.  However, you have been given the challenge of estimating  the costs for your nuclear reactor project. A basic assumption that you need to make early in this process is—","R1":"How direct and indirect costs will be handled","R2":"Whether or not experts will be available to assist you in this process","R3":"If there will be a multiyear project budget","R4":"Whether the project has required delivery dates ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Overall cost estimates must be allocated to individual activities to establish the cost performance baseline.  In an ideal situation, a project manager would prefer to  prepare estimates—","R1":"Before the budget is complete","R2":"After the budget is approved by management","R3":"Using a parametric estimating technique and model specific for that project type","R4":"Using a bottom-up estimating technique ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"As project manager, you identified a number of acceptable tolerances as part of your earned value management system. During execution, some \"unacceptable\" variances  occurred. After each \"unacceptable\" variance occurred,  you did which one of the following first?","R1":"Updated the budget","R2":"Prepared a revised cost estimate","R3":"Adjusted the project plan","R4":"Documented lessons learned ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Assume that the project cost estimates have been prepared for each activity and the basis of these estimates has been determined. Now, as the project manager for  your nutrition awareness program in your hospital, you  are preparing your budget. Because you have estimates  for more than 1,200 separate activities, you have decided  to first—","R1":"Aggregate these estimates by work packages","R2":"Aggregate these estimates by control accounts to facilitate the use of earned value management","R3":"Use the results of previous projects to predict total costs","R4":"Set your cost performance baseline ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The cumulative cost curve for planned and actual expenditures—","R1":"Helps to monitor project performance at a glance","R2":"Is used for calculating the CPI","R3":"Is also known as a histogram","R4":"Forecasts total project expenditures ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Quality is very important to your company. Each project has a quality statement that is consistent with the organization’s vision and mission. Both internal and external  quality assurance are provided on all projects to—","R1":"Ensure confidence that the project will satisfy relevant","R2":"Monitor specific project results to note whether they comply with relevant quality standards","R3":"Identify ways to eliminate causes of unsatisfactory results","R4":"Use inspection to keep errors out of the process ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The quality function deployment process is used to—","R1":"Provide better product definition and product","R2":"Help products to succeed in the marketplace","R3":"Improve the functional characteristics of a product","R4":"Support production planning and the just-in-time approach ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The project team should have a working knowledge of statistical process control to help evaluate control quality  outputs. Of all the topics involved, which of the following  is the most important for the team to understand?","R1":"Sampling and probability","R2":"Attribute sampling and variables sampling","R3":"Tolerances and control limits","R4":"Special causes and random causes ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Project quality management was once thought to include only inspection or quality control. In recent years, the  concept of project quality management has broadened.  Which statement is NOT representative of the new definition of quality management?","R1":"Quality is designed into the product or service, not","R2":"Quality is the concern of the quality assurance staff.","R3":"Customers require a documented and, in some cases, registered quality assurance system.","R4":"National and international standards and guidelines for quality assurance systems are available. ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You are managing a major international project, and your contract requires you to prepare both a project plan and  a quality management plan. Your core team is  preparing  a project quality management plan. Your first step in  developing this plan is to—","R1":"Determine specific metrics to use in the quality","R2":"Identify the quality standards for the project","R3":"Develop a quality policy for the project","R4":"Identify specific quality management roles and responsibilities for the project ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Recently your company introduced a new set of \"metal woods\" to its established line of golfing   equipment.  However, in the past weeks many of the clubs have been  returned because of quality problems. You decide to  conduct a failure mode and criticality analysis to—","R1":"Analyze the product development cycle after product","R2":"Evaluate failure modes and causes associated with the design and manufacture of this product","R3":"Evaluate failure modes and causes  associated with the design and manufacture of a new  product to replace the clubs","R4":"Help management set priorities in its existing manufacturing processes to avoid failures ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The ISO 9000 standards provide—","R1":"A description of how products should be produced","R2":"Specifics for the implementation of quality systems","R3":"A framework for quality systems","R4":"The maximum process requirements necessary to ensure that customers receive a good product ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"There are three uses and types of Pareto analysis. If you wish to provide a measure of significance to factors that  at first may not appear to be significant at all, you should  use a—","R1":"Basic Pareto analysis","R2":"Comparative Pareto analysis","R3":"Weighted Pareto analysis","R4":"Trend Pareto analysis ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The quality management plan describes all the following EXCEPT the—","R1":"Method for implementing the quality policy","R2":"Methods the team will use to meet the project’s quality  requirements","R3":"Efforts at the front end of a project to ensure that decisions are based on accurate information","R4":"Procedures used to conduct trade-off analyses among cost, schedule, and quality  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You are leading a team to recommend an equitable reward and recognition system for project managers .  Before finalizing the plan, you want to ensure that  executives understand the basic objective of reward  systems. This objective is to—","R1":"Be comparable with the award system established for","R2":"Make the link between project performance and reward clear, explicit, and achievable","R3":"Motivate project managers to work toward common objectives and goals as defined by the company","R4":"Attract people to join the organization’s project management career path ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"As you prepare your human resource plan, you need to determine the skill and capacity required to complete  the activities in the project. This should be documented  in the—","R1":"Roles and responsibilities section","R2":"Staffing management plan","R3":"Staff acquisition section","R4":"Compliance section ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The primary result of effective team development is—","R1":"Improved project performance","R2":"An effective, smoothly running team","R3":"An understanding by project team members that the project manager is ultimately responsible for  project performance","R4":"Enhancement of the ability of stakeholders to contribute as individuals and team members ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Given that you are neighbors, you and the CEO of your company have established a friendly personal relationship.  Recently your company appointed you project  manager  for a new project that is crucial to achieving next year’s  financial targets. Which type of power available to project  managers might you be able to rely upon?","R1":"Referent","R2":"Reward","R3":"Formal","R4":"Expert ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"You have been a project manager for seven years. You now are managing the construction of a new facility that  must comply with the government’s newly issued environmental standards. You want to ensure that your team  members are able to select methods to complete various  activities on the project without needing to involve you  in each situation. As you prepare your human resource  management plan, you should document this information  in which of the following—","R1":"Roles and responsibilities section","R2":"Resource assignment matrix","R3":"Resource breakdown structure","R4":"Staffing management plan ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"In both the weak and strong matrix organizational structures, the primary condition leading to conflict is—","R1":"Communication barriers","R2":"Conflicting interests","R3":"Need for consensus","R4":"Ambiguous jurisdictions ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You are part of a team that is working to develop a new medical implant device. Your project manager is an  expert in medical implantation devices, yet he continually  seeks opinions from the team about a wide variety of  project and product issues. Team members often run  project meetings while he sits silently at the head of the  table. Which one of the following best characterizes his  leadership style?","R1":"Laissez-faire","R2":"Team directed","R3":"Collaborative","R4":"Shared leadership ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The major difference between the project coordinator and project expeditor forms of organization is that—","R1":"Strong commitment to the project usually does not","R2":"The project coordinator cannot personally make or enforce decisions","R3":"The project expeditor acts only as an intermediary between management and the project team","R4":"The project coordinator reports to a higher-level manager in the organization ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Which one of the following represents a constraint on the acquire project team process?","R1":"Preassignment of staff to the project","R2":"Recruitment practices of the organizations involved","R3":"Use of outsourcing","R4":"Team member training requirements ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"According to Herzberg’s Motivator-Hygiene Theory, when achievement, recognition, responsibility, and advancement,  or promotion, are not present, employees will—","R1":"Become alienated with the organization and leave","R2":"Lack motivation but will not be dissatisfied with their work","R3":"Lack motivation and become dissatisfied with their work","R4":"Become dissatisfied only if they do not receive salary increases ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Your organization is adopting a project-based approach to business, which has been difficult. Although project teams  have been created, they are little more than a collection  of functional and technical experts who focus on their  specialties. You are managing the company’s most important project. As you begin this project, you must place a  high priority on—","R1":"Creating an effective team","R2":"Identifying the resources needed to finish the project on time","R3":"The best way to communicate status to the CEO","R4":"Establishing firm project requirements ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Hierarchical-type charts are a tool and technique for use in human resource planning. Which one of the following  is helpful in tracking project costs and can be aligned  with the organization’s accounting system?","R1":"RACI","R2":"RAM","R3":"RBS","R4":"OBS ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"You are managing a project with team members located at customer sites on three different continents. As you  plan communications with your stakeholders, you  should review—","R1":"Stakeholder management plan","R2":"Stakeholder register","R3":"Communications model","R4":"Communications channels ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Having worked previously on projects as a team   member, you are pleased to now be the project manager to  develop a new process to ensure that software projects  in your IT Department are considered a success and are  not late or over budget. However, many of your team  members are new to the organization. As you work  to establish a high-performing team, you realize the  importance  of—","R1":"Mentoring","R2":"Coaching","R3":"Moving quickly through the forming and storming stages","R4":"Safeguarding information ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Your company CEO just sent you an e-mail asking you to make a presentation on your project, which has been  in progress for 18 months, to over 50 identified internal  and external stakeholders. You have been conducting  such presentations and holding meetings regularly on this  important project. You should begin by—","R1":"Defining the audience","R2":"Determining the objective","R3":"Deciding on the general form of the presentation","R4":"Circulating issues to be discussed ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Sample attributes of a communications management plan include which one of the following?","R1":"Roles","R2":"Responsibilities","R3":"Ethics","R4":"Authority ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"In project communications, the first step in a written communication is to—","R1":"Analyze the facts and assumptions that have a bearing","R2":"Gather thoughts or ideas","R3":"Develop a logical sequence of the topics to be addressed","R4":"Establish the basic purpose of the message ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"A communications management plan includes which one of the following sample contents?","R1":"Issues","R2":"Escalation processes, including time frames and the management chains","R3":"Dimensions","R4":"Project assumptions and constraints ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Your organization has decided to use project management for all of its endeavors. It has established a Center of Excellence for Project Management to support the movement into management by projects and has appointed  you as its director. Since you work in a matrix environment, which of the following types of communications is  the most essential for success?","R1":"Upward","R2":"Horizontal","R3":"Downward","R4":"Diagonal ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You have heard recently that the client calls your progress reports the \"Code of Hammurabi\" because they seem to be  written in hieroglyphics and are completely  indecipherable  to all but an antiquities scholar. This situation could have  been avoided by—","R1":"Informing the client at the start of the project about","R2":"Using risk management techniques to identify client issues","R3":"Hiring an expert report writer to prepare standard reports","R4":"Engaging in communications planning ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Changes in the report formats and lessons learned documents process should trigger changes to the—","R1":"Project management plan and performance","R2":"Integrated change control system and the communications management plan","R3":"Monitor and control project process and the project management plan","R4":"Organizational process assets updates ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"One way to determine how to best update and communicate project performance and respond to stakeholder information requests is to—","R1":"Review the effectiveness of the communications","R2":"Set up a portal","R3":"Hold meetings","R4":"Distribute performance reports ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Because communications planning often is linked tightly with enterprise environmental factors, which one of the  following statements is true?","R1":"The project’s organizational structure has a major","R2":"Standardized guidelines, work instructions, and performance measurement criteria are key items to consider.","R3":"Procedures for approving and issuing work authorizations should be taken into consideration.","R4":"Criteria and guidelines to tailor standard processes to the specific needs of the project should be stated  explicitly. ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"You are working on identifying possible risks to your project to develop a nutritional supplement. You want  to develop a comprehensive list of risks that can be  addressed later through qualitative and quantitative risk  analysis. An information gathering technique used to  identify risks is—","R1":"Documentation reviews","R2":"Probability and impact analysis","R3":"Checklist analysis","R4":"Brainstorming ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"A recent earned value analysis shows that your project is 20 percent complete, the CPI is 0.67, and the SPI is 0.87.  In this situation, you should—","R1":"Perform additional resource planning, add resources,","R2":"Rebaseline the schedule, then use Monte Carlo analysis","R3":"Conduct a risk response audit to help control risk","R4":"Forecast potential deviation of the project at completion from cost and schedule targets ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The purpose of a numeric scale in risk management is to—","R1":"Avoid high-impact risks","R2":"Assign a relative value to the impact on project objectives if the risk in question occurs","R3":"Rank order risks in terms of very low, low, moderate, high, and very high","R4":"Test project assumptions ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"The primary advantage of using decision-tree analysis in project risk management is that it—","R1":"Considers the attitude of the decision maker toward risk","R2":"Forces consideration of the probability of each outcome","R3":"Helps to identify and postulate risk scenarios for the project","R4":"Shows how risks can occur in combination ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"When managing current projects, it is important to use lessons learned from previous projects to improve the  organization’s project management process. Therefore, in  project closing procedures, it is important to review the—","R1":"Secondary risks that occurred","R2":"Checklists for identify risks","R3":"WBS dictionary","R4":"Fallback plan ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Which one of the following statements best characterizes an activity cost or duration estimate developed with a  limited amount of information?","R1":"It should be part of the planning for the needed","R2":"It is an input to identify risks.","R3":"It is an output from identify risks.","R4":"It must be factored into the list of prioritized project risks. ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"What is the primary difference between a risk audit and a risk reassessment?","R1":"A risk reassessment is conducted at the completion of","R2":"Project stakeholders conduct risk audits; management conducts reassessments.","R3":"Risk reassessments are regularly scheduled; risk audits are performed as defined in the project’s risk management plan.","R4":"There is no difference; they are virtually the same. ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Assigning more talented resources to the project to reduce time to completion or to provide better quality  than  originally planned are examples of which one of the  following  strategies?","R1":"Enhance","R2":"Exploit","R3":"Share","R4":"Contingent response ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"What doctrine causes a party to relinquish rights under a contract because it knowingly fails to execute  those rights?","R1":"Assignment of claims","R2":"Material breach","R3":"Waiver","R4":"Warranties ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Significant differences between the seller’s price and your independent estimate may indicate all the following  EXCEPT the—","R1":"SOW was not adequate","R2":"Seller misunderstood the SOW","R3":"Sellers failed to respond","R4":"Project team chose the wrong contract type ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"When a seller breaches a contract, the buyer cannot receive—","R1":"Compensatory damages","R2":"Punitive damages","R3":"Liquidated damages","R4":"Consequential damages ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Because you are working under a firm-fixed-price contract, management wants you to submit the final  invoice and close out the contract as soon as possible.  Before final payment on the contract can be authorized,  you must—","R1":"Prepare a contract completion statement","R2":"Audit the procurement process","R3":"Update and archive contract records","R4":"Settle subcontracts ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Recent data indicate that more than 10,000 airline passengers are injured each year from baggage that falls from overhead bins. You performed a make-or-buy analysis  and decided to outsource an improved bin design and  manufacture. The project team needs to develop a list of  qualified sources. As a general rule, which method would  the project team find especially helpful?","R1":"Advertising","R2":"Internet","R3":"Trade catalogs","R4":"Relevant local associations ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Your company decided to award a contract for   project management services on a pharmaceutical research  project. Because your company is new to project management and does not understand the full scope of services  that may be needed under the contract, it is most appropriate to award a—","R1":"Firm-fixed-price contract","R2":"Fixed-price-incentive contract","R3":"Cost-plus-a-percentage-of-cost contract","R4":"Time-and-materials contract ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The principal function of a warranty is to—","R1":"Provide assurance of the level of quality to be provided","R2":"Provide a way to assert claims for late payment","R3":"Provide a way to allow additional time following acceptance to correct deficiencies, without additional costs","R4":"Ensure that goods purchased fit the purposes for which they are to be used ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"As project manager, you need a relatively fast and informal method addressing disagreements with contractors. One such method is to submit the issue in question to  an impartial third party for resolution. This process is  known as—","R1":"Alternative dispute resolution","R2":"Problem processing","R3":"Steering resolution","R4":"Mediation litigation ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"A no-cost settlement sometimes is used—","R1":"To close out a successful contract","R2":"In lieu of formal termination procedures","R3":"When buyer property has been furnished under the contract","R4":"When such an arrangement is acceptable to one of the parties involved ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"When writing payment terms in your fixed-price subcontracts it is especially important to—","R1":"Include incentives if the seller exceeds or fails below","R2":"Provide flexibility to redirect the seller if the scope of work is not defined precisely confusion","R3":"Link progress made to compensation paid","R4":"Associate the payment to a specific time period for more efficient accounting ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"During your project, you will have a number of different types of meetings. Some will be informational, others will  be key updates, and some will be for decision-making  purposes. While different attendees will attend each meeting, a best practice to follow is to:","R1":"Group stakeholders into categories to determine which","R2":"Invite those stakeholders who have a high level of interest in your project to attend each meeting","R3":"Be sensitive to the fact that stakeholders often have very different objectives","R4":"Recognize that roles and responsibilities may overlap but practice a policy of ‘no surprises’ and inform your  stakeholders about any upcoming meetings ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Recognizing the importance of preparing a stakeholder management plan, you met with your team to obtain their  buy in and to discuss it. You explained the key benefit of  plan stakeholder management is to—","R1":"Determine appropriate strategies for a continual focus","R2":"Provide a clear plan that is actionable to interact with stakeholders to support the project’s interests","R3":"Develop appropriate management strategies to effectively engage stakeholders","R4":"Plan a series of meetings to ensure stakeholders remain interested and to address their concerns ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Assume you are actively working, along with your team, to manage stakeholder engagement on your project to  develop a new drug to prevent any retina problems of  any type. You know you must manage their engagement  throughout the project life cycle. This means some organizational process assets will need updating including—","R1":"Informal and formal project reports","R2":"The stakeholder register","R3":"The stakeholder management plan","R4":"Work performance information ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"As you work on your project to update its software training classes to focus on an agile approach, you have a number of key stakeholders. As many students and their  managers are requesting these classes, your CEO has  taken a special interest in your project and has asked you  to accelerate your schedule to complete it in two months  rather than in your planned six months but still have  quality offerings. This means as you work to monitor  overall project stakeholder relationships, you should—","R1":"Provide notifications to stakeholders about status regularly","R2":"Ask your stakeholders for regular feedback as you work on your project","R3":"Provide presentations to each stakeholder group","R4":"Determine how changes will be monitored and controlled ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"As you work with your team to prepare your stakeholder management plan, you decided to develop a stakeholder  engagement chart. You set it up so you could—","R1":"Show the phase of your project of interest to identified stakeholders","R2":"Show gaps between current and desired levels of engagement","R3":"Determine which stakeholders you and your team felt were critical to project success but did not know about it","R4":"Determine when to involve key stakeholders in your project ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"A number of items in the stakeholder management plan are similar to those in the communications management  plan. An example is—","R1":"Method for updating and refining the plans as the","R2":"Stakeholder communication requirements for the current project phase","R3":"Information to be distributed to stakeholders including language, format, content, and level of detail","R4":"Time frame and frequency for the distribution of required information to stakeholders ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Having worked as a project manager for nine years, you know how important it is to identify the critical stakeholders so you do not overlook anyone who has a major  influence on your project even if you do not ever plan to  meet with or talk with this individual. As you work with  your team, you explain the key benefit of the identify  stakeholder process is that it—","R1":"Identifies the people, groups, or organizations that","R2":"Shows the interdependencies among project stakeholders to enable classification for how best to involve them on your project","R3":"Identifies the appropriate focus for each stakeholder or a group of stakeholders","R4":"Shows the potential impact each stakeholder has on project success ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Stakeholder engagement involves a number of critical activities. An example is—","R1":"Ensuring goals are met through negotiation and","R2":"Developing management strategies to engage them during the project’s life cycle","R3":"Adjusting strategies and plans to engage stakeholders  effectively","R4":"Identifying the scope and impact of changes to project stakeholders ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Often in working as a project manager, it is easy to overlook key stakeholders. Assume you work for a device manufacturer and are working as the project manager for  the next generation valve replacement. Your company has  been a leader in this market, which means you have a lot  of lessons learned available to you. Your project is scheduled to last four years. As a best practice, you should—","R1":"Work actively with your company’s Knowledge","R2":"Consult regularly with your program manager","R3":"Work actively with members of your Governance Board","R4":"Work actively with members of your company’s Portfolio Review Board ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Assume you have identified your stakeholders and are preparing your stakeholder management plan. You are  fortunate that your team is a collocated team as you  are working on an internal project to reorganize your  IT Department so it is focused more on its customers.  The project sponsor is the Chief Operating Officer, and  the IT Department Director was surprised as she thought  all was well. However, you notice when planning meetings are held, the Chief Financial Officer never attends.  You feel since IT affects the entire company, all the senior  leaders need some type of involvement. You therefore feel  the Chief Financial Officer may be—","R1":"Resistant","R2":"Unaware","R3":"Uninterested","R4":"Satisfied ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The stakeholder register should not be prepared only one time, but it should be updated regularly especially if—","R1":"The stakeholder is not an active participant","R2":"The stakeholder is not impacted by the project","R3":"The stakeholder does not read status updates","R4":"The stakeholder leads a corporate reorganization ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Working to foster stakeholder engagement, as the project manager, you know a combination of interpersonal skills  and general management skills is needed. An example of  an key interpersonal skill in stakeholder engagement is—","R1":"Facilitating consensus","R2":"Influencing people","R3":"Resolving conflicts","R4":"Negotiating agreements ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Expert judgment is a best practice as a tool and technique in many project management processes, and the list of  possible sources for experts varies by the organization and  by its association with others. One way once you have identified experts who you feel could be of assistance is to—","R1":"Use a focus group","R2":"Review documentation","R3":"Hold one-on-one interviews","R4":"Conduct interviews ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Recognizing operations management is different than project management, as the project manager for a new  line of electrical tractors to avoid the need to use costly  fuel, you realize a best practice is to—","R1":"Document the operational managers’ influence either","R2":"Offer to include the operational managers in all project  phases","R3":"Recognize that the operational managers are only involved once they have ongoing responsibility for the  product, service, or result","R4":"Realize the operations managers have key responsibilities on the Portfolio Review Board ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"One way to develop an understanding of major project stakeholders to exchange and analyze project information  about roles and interests is to—","R1":"Conduct interviews","R2":"Hold profile analysis meetings","R3":"Use questionnaires and surveys","R4":"Conduct a stakeholder analysis and analyze the results with a focus group ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Assume you are managing a project to implement an electronic medical record system in your   ophthalmologist’s  office. You have been working to identify your stakeholders to then make sure everyone is committed to  it as some people have been working in this office for  more than 20 years and are comfortable with the manual  approach. At this point, you have documented assessment  information, which includes—","R1":"Role in the project","R2":"Whether the stakeholder is a supporter, is neutral, or is resistant","R3":"Potential influence in the project","R4":"Organization position ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Having prepared stakeholder management plans on previous projects, you know it is positive to review the  project management plan because it—","R1":"Provides information as to how to plan appropriate","R2":"Contains information useful to ensure the stakeholder management plan is aligned with the organization’s culture","R3":"Helps to determine the best options to support an adaptive process for stakeholder management","R4":"Contains a change management plan and documents how changes will be monitored and controlled ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Working on your project to design and construct five new bridges for your City, you are striving to actively manage  the stakeholders on your project, especially those who  will be inconvenienced by the project and have indicated  they do not support it. You decided to review your communications management plan as it—","R1":"Contains issue management procedures","R2":"Describes the project’s life cycle and the processes to be used in each phase","R3":"Sets forth an escalation process","R4":"Provides guidance as to how to best involve stakeholders in the project ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"A supporting input for controlling stakeholder engagement is—","R1":"Budget","R2":"Project schedule","R3":"Historical information","R4":"Number of defects ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"As a result of the control stakeholder expectations process, you realize even though this process is under way until the closing phase that you have identified the root  cause of some issues you have faced in controlling stakeholders expectations. You should therefore—","R1":"Review them with your Governance Board","R2":"Revise and reissue your stakeholder management plan","R3":"Prepare a change request","R4":"Update the lessons learned documentation ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Table reporting, spreadsheet analysis, and presentations are examples of—","R1":"Project reports as an input to manage stakeholder","R2":"Work performance information as an output of control stakeholder engagement","R3":"Tools and techniques used in control stakeholder engagement","R4":"Updates from the plan stakeholder management process","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"In the initial stage of the project life cycle, the project’s technical objectives are apt to be understood only in a  general sense. A major component of project conflict  during this stage of the project is—","R1":"Concerns over priorities and procedures","R2":"Concerns about technical issues","R3":"Schedules","R4":"Confusion of establishing a project in the matrix management  environment ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"On your project to construct a new runway for your City’s airport, you are in the process of selecting vendors  for various parts of this project. You have conducted  your make-or-buy analysis and have issued Requests  for Proposals. You believe it is important to examine  past performance of potential vendors. This means you  are using—","R1":"Proposal evaluation techniques","R2":"Multi-disciplinary review teams","R3":"Analytical techniques","R4":"Independent estimates ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Requirements typically are classified into product requirements and project requirements. Capturing and managing both types of requirements is important for project success, so you and your team decided to follow this  classification system on your project to modernize all the  telecommunications equipment in your company. During  such an approach, all the following are examples of  product requirements EXCEPT—","R1":"Action requirements","R2":"Level of service requirements","R3":"Security requirements","R4":"Performance requirements ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Although the project charter serves to state the project manager’s authority and responsibility on the project,  the project manager further requires which type of power  in order to be an effective leader?","R1":"Expert","R2":"Legitimate","R3":"Position","R4":"Referent ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"A number of tools and techniques are helpful in the perform integrated change control process. If you want  to implement an integrated change control process, you  should use—","R1":"Configuration management software","R2":"A project management information system","R3":"Project status review meetings","R4":"Change control meetings ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"During the closing phase of the project, the top-ranked source of conflict is—","R1":"Schedule","R2":"Administrative procedures","R3":"Cost","R4":"Human resources ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The project scope baseline should be used in the identify risks process because it—","R1":"Identifies project assumptions","R2":"Identifies all work that must be done; therefore, it includes all risks on the project","R3":"Helps organize all work that must be done on the project","R4":"Contains information on risks from prior projects ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Although there are various tools and techniques to consider as you collect requirements on your project,  one approach that supports the concept of progressive  elaboration  is—","R1":"Idea/mind mapping","R2":"Affinity diagrams","R3":"Prototypes","R4":"Joint Application Design ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Although your company’s project life cycle does not mandate when a project review should be conducted,  you believe it is important to review performance at the  conclusion of each phase. The objective of such a review  is to—","R1":"Determine how many resources are required to","R2":"Adjust the schedule and cost baselines based on past performance","R3":"Obtain customer acceptance of project deliverables","R4":"Determine whether the project should continue to the next phase ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The key management skills required during the adjourning stage of team development include all but which one of the following?","R1":"Evaluating","R2":"Reviewing","R3":"Celebrating","R4":"Improving ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The CPI on your project is 0.44, which means that you should—","R1":"Place emphasis on improving the timeliness of the","R2":"Reassess the life-cycle costs of your product, including the length of the life-cycle phase","R3":"Place emphasis on improving the productivity by which work was being performed","R4":"Recognize that your original estimates were fundamentally flawed, and your project is in an atypical situation ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Project deliverables are the outputs that include the product , service, or result of the project as well as  ancillary results. These ancillary results should be in the—","R1":"Requirements management plan","R2":"Scope management plan","R3":"Project scope statement","R4":"Project acceptance criteria ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"One key reason that the develop project charter process is so important is that it—","R1":"Documents the boundaries of the project","R2":"States the methods for acceptance of the project’s deliverables","R3":"Describes the project’s characteristics","R4":"Links the project to the ongoing work of the organization ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Assume you had a phase gate meeting with your Governance Board for your project to develop the next  generation radar system as part of the nation’s airspace  modernization program. At this meeting, the Board  approved your project management plan. However, as  you begin to execute your plan, an organizational process  asset to consider is—","R1":"Stakeholder risk tolerances","R2":"The organization’s culture","R3":"Hiring and firing guidelines","R4":"Process measurement data base ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Your experience has taught you that inappropriate  responses to cost variances can produce quality or schedule problems or unacceptable project risk. When leading  a team meeting to discuss the importance of cost control,  you note that cost control is concerned with—","R1":"Influencing the factors that create change to the","R2":"Developing an approximation of the costs of the resources needed to complete the project","R3":"Allocating the overall cost estimate to individual work items","R4":"Establishing a cost performance baseline ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"You are pleased to be the project manager for a new video conferencing system for your global organization.  You want it to be one that is easy to use and is state of  the art. As the project manager, you also are the project  leader. You realize leadership is critical throughout the  phases of the project and its key elements are—","R1":"Respect and trust","R2":"Political and cultural awareness","R3":"Negotiation and influencing","R4":"Decision making and conflict management ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The WBS represents all product and project work, including project management. It is sometimes called the—","R1":"Control account level","R2":"100% rule","R3":"Integration of scope, cost, and schedule for comparison to the earned value","R4":"The code of accounts ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You are trying to determine whether or not to conduct 100% final system tests of 500 ground-based radar units  at the factory. The historical radar field failure rate is 4%;  the cost to test each unit in the factory is $10,000; the cost  to reassemble each passed unit after the factory test is  $2,000; the cost to repair and reassemble each failed unit  after factory test is $23,000; and the cost to repair and  reinstall each failed unit in the field is $350,000. Using  decision tree analysis, what is the expected value if you  decide to conduct these tests?","R1":"$5.5 million","R2":"$5.96 million","R3":"$6.42 million","R4":"$7 million ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"One output of the control costs process is cost forecasts, which is when—","R1":"Modifications are made to the cost information used","R2":"Trend analyses are performed and communicated to stakeholders","R3":"A budget update is required and communicated to all stakeholders","R4":"A calculated EAC value or a bottom-up EAC value is documented and communicated to stakeholders ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"At the time the risk register is first prepared, it should contain all the following entries EXCEPT—","R1":"Root causes of risk","R2":"Structure for describing risks","R3":"List of risks requiring near-term responses","R4":"List of potential responses ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"All the following are examples of project document updates from the manage project team process EXCEPT—","R1":"Issue log","R2":"Roles description","R3":"Project staff assignments","R4":"Personnel skills ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Recording and reporting information regarding when appropriate configuration information should be  provided  and regarding the status of proposed and approved  changes effectively is done through—","R1":"Configuration status accounting","R2":"Configuration verification and audit","R3":"Project management methodology","R4":"A project management information system (PMIS) ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Activity attributes are used to extend the description of the activity and to identify its multiple components.  In the early stages of the project, an example of an  activity  attribute  is—","R1":"Activity codes","R2":"Activity description","R3":"Predecessor and successor activities","R4":"Activity name ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You are working on a project and want to know how many activities in the previous month were completed  with significant variances. You should use a(n)—","R1":"Control chart","R2":"Inspection","R3":"Scatter diagram","R4":"Trend analysis ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"If you decide to follow an open subordination approach to resolving conflict, you are using which style of conflict  resolution?","R1":"Avoiding","R2":"Accommodating","R3":"Compromising","R4":"Collaborating ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Working in the control procurements process since your project is using five contractors, you need to update a  number of organizational process assets. An example is—","R1":"Procurement management plan","R2":"Procurement documentation","R3":"Correspondence","R4":"Warranties ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"All of the following are examples of ways to generate options for mutual gain during negotiations EXCEPT—","R1":"Separating inventing from deciding","R2":"Options broadening","R3":"Zero-sum game analysis","R4":"Multiplying options by shuttling between the specific and the general ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Schedule control is one important way to avoid delays. While planning and executing schedule recovery, one tool  available to you for control schedules is—","R1":"Changing the schedule management plan","R2":"Immediately rebaselining","R3":"Adjusting leads and lags","R4":"Changing all project and resource calendars ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"All the following statements are true about the grassroots estimate, EXCEPT—","R1":"Its accuracy rate is from –5% to +10%","R2":"It is also called an engineering estimate","R3":"It is used primarily for Level 1 of the WBS","R4":"It may take months to prepare ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Assume that you are managing a project team. Your team is one in which its members confront issues rather than  people, establish procedures collectively, and is team  oriented. As the project manager, which of the  following  represents your team’s stage of development and the  approach you should use during this time?","R1":"Storming; high directive and supportive approach","R2":"Norming; high directive and low supportive approach","R3":"Norming; high supportive and low directive approach","R4":"Performing; low directive and supportive approach ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"You are working on a project and want to identify the cause of problems in a process by the shape and width  of the distribution of the process variables. You should  use a—","R1":"Histogram","R2":"Pareto chart","R3":"Scatter diagram","R4":"Trend analysis ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Assume that you were the first person in your company to be PMP certified and also that you earned a doctorate  in project management. People throughout the organization admired your achievements. Based on your success  in managing projects, your company now has adopted  a management-by-projects philosophy. You have been  appointed head of your company’s project management  office to lead the organization as it transitions to this new  way of working. So far, people seem to willingly comply  with your demands and requests. In this situation, you are  using which type of power?","R1":"Legitimate","R2":"Expert","R3":"Contacts","R4":"Referent ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The nature of project work is such that it inevitably causes stress. Project managers thus need to learn how  to cope with and manage stress and understand what  stress is and why it is created. Project managers need to  note that it can be a positive experience depending on  how people perceive stress and should work to mentor team members accordingly. As you strive to become  more aware of stress, which one of the following is NOT  considered a stress-creating factor that is related to the  project environment?","R1":"Role ambiguity","R2":"Corporate politics","R3":"Career development","R4":"Selection of team members ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". Assume you are working as the project manager on the first project in your company to use the critical chain  approach to scheduling. You are a PMP and also are  certified in critical chain. You are getting ready for a  performance review with your Governance Board,  and you can expect they will ask questions about—","R1":"The magnitude of variance against the schedule baseline","R2":"Schedule risk","R3":"Performance to date since the past review meeting","R4":"The buffer needed and buffer remaining ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":". A number of approaches can be helpful when estimating resource requirements for activities on a project. Assume  you are managing a project and you have already prepared your WBS. When you decomposed your WBS, it  has 45 work packages. You then prepared an activity list.  Now, you are preparing your schedule and determining  your resource requirements. You found there were about  30 activities that you could not estimate with a reasonable  degree of confidence, so you and your team decided to  use which one of the following approaches to help with  these activity resource estimates:","R1":"Resource breakdown structure","R2":"Published estimating data","R3":"Alternatives analysis","R4":"Bottom-up estimating ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":". To practice effective schedule control, your project team must be alert to any issues that may cause problems in  the future. To best accomplish effective schedule control,  the team should—","R1":"Review work performance information","R2":"Allow no changes to the schedule","R3":"Update the schedule management plan on a continuous basis","R4":"Hold status reviews ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". You are the project manager for a major logistics installation project and must obtain specific services from local sources external to your project. Your subcontracts  administrator has told you to prepare a product or service  description, which is referenced in a—","R1":"Project statement of work","R2":"Contract scope statement","R3":"Request for proposal","R4":"Contract ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". Your company is embarking on a project to launch a new product delivery service. You are the project manager  for this project and have just finished the concept phase.  The various outputs/deliverable(s) for this phase include—","R1":"Project management plan","R2":"Scope of work and requirements","R3":"Project charter and stakeholder register","R4":"Roles and responsibilities of the project manager ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":". Team building should be ongoing throughout the project life cycle. However, it is hard to maintain momentum and  morale, especially on large, complex projects that span  several years. One guideline to follow to promote team  building is to—","R1":"Consider every meeting a team meeting, not the","R2":"Conduct team building at specific times during the project through off-site meetings","R3":"Engage the services of a full-time facilitator before any team-building initiatives are conducted","R4":"Develop the project schedule using the services of a project control officer and then issue it immediately to  the team ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". You have been assigned as the project manager for a major project in your company where the customer and  key supplier are located in another country. You have  been working on your project for six months. Recently,  you traveled to this country, and at the conclusion of  a critical design review meeting, which was highly  successful, you realized you were successful in building a  high-performing team. You had your own team members,  who work in a weak matrix structure, on a conference  call during this meeting. Although it was difficult to reach  agreement on some key issues, you therefore relied on  your interpersonal skills in—","R1":"Facilitation","R2":"Negotiating","R3":"Influencing","R4":"Decision making ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":". You are leading a team to review and improve the  project selection and prioritization method. You know that the  two most important questions to answer are \"can we do  the project?\" (feasibility study) and \"should we do the  project?\" (cost-benefit analysis). The team is considering  many different management concerns, including financial return, market share, and public perception. The most  important criterion for building a project selection  model is—","R1":"Risks","R2":"Realism","R3":"Ease of use","R4":"Benefits realization ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":". On your systems development project, you noted during a review that the system had less functionality than planned  at the critical design review. This note suggests that  during  the control risks process you used which following  tools and techniques?","R1":"Risk reassessment","R2":"Variance analysis","R3":"Technical performance measurement","R4":"Reserve analysis ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":". Contested changes are requested changes when the buyer and seller cannot agree on compensation for the  change. They are also known as all but which one of the  following?","R1":"Disputes","R2":"Demands","R3":"Appeals","R4":"Claims ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":". A structured review of the seller’s progress to deliver project scope and quality within cost and schedule is  known as a(n)—","R1":"Procurement performance review","R2":"Procurement audit","R3":"Inspection","R4":"Status review meeting ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". A number of different decision-making styles can be used in a team environment. When quality and acceptance  are both important, which of the following styles should  be used?","R1":"Command","R2":"Consultation","R3":"Consensus","R4":"Coin flip ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":". Historical information is used—","R1":"To compare current performance with prospective","R2":"To prepare the stakeholder management plan","R3":"To evaluate the skills and competencies of prospective team members","R4":"As an input to develop project charter ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":". Two team members on your current construction project are engaged in a major argument concerning the selection  of project management software. They refuse to listen  to each other. The most appropriate conflict resolution  approach for you to use in this situation is—","R1":"Accommodating","R2":"Compromising","R3":"Collaborating","R4":"Forcing ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":". As you use the critical chain method in lieu of the critical  path method in developing your schedule,  assume you have determined the buffer schedule  activities . Your planned activities are scheduled to their  latest possible planed start and end dates. Therefore,  you are focusing on—","R1":"Managing the free float of each network path","R2":"Managing the total float of the network paths","R3":"Managing remaining buffer durations against the remaining durations of task chains","R4":"Managing the total buffer durations against the durations of the task chains ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":". You have been placed in charge of a group of people that is selecting one of three possible projects. As you gather  in the conference room, many team members already  have decided which project selection technique to use.  Some prefer IRR, and others argue for BCR. In deciding  which method to use, your first step should be to—","R1":"Compare and contrast selection techniques and identify the advantages and disadvantage of each","R2":"Identify the technique used most often in the company and determine if it is appropriate for this project","R3":"Select the method for which most team members have knowledge","R4":"Determine the philosophy and wishes of management ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":". Before considering a project closed, what document should be reviewed to ensure that project scope has  been satisfied?","R1":"Project scope statement","R2":"Project management plan","R3":"Project closeout checklists","R4":"Scope management plan ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":". A cost management plan should establish and document the various earned value rules of performance measurement. Along with defining the WBS to the level that the  earned value analysis will be performed and establishing  how earned value will be credited to the project (0-100,  0-50-100, and so on), which following rule is also recognized regarding performance measurement?","R1":"Determine the formula for calculating the estimate to","R2":"Determine the code of accounts allocation provision for the WBS","R3":"Determine the formula for calculating the estimate at completion (EAC) for the project","R4":"Determine the variance thresholds to be used in the project ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":". You have a conflict on your team but have enough time to resolve it, and you want to maintain future relationships. Thankfully, there is mutual trust, respect, and  confidence among the parties involved. You decide to  use confronting to resolve this conflict. In using this  approach, your first step should be to—","R1":"Separate people from the problem","R2":"Acknowledge that conflict exists","R3":"Establish ground rules","R4":"Explore alternatives ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":". One way to evaluate the project schedule performance is to—","R1":"Use the project management information system (PMIS)","R2":"Determine the percent complete of in-progress schedule  activities","R3":"Establish a schedule change control system","R4":"Determine the total float variance ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":". You completed your stakeholder analysis. How do you want to manage those stakeholders that have a high  interest in your project and high power over decisions  affecting your project?","R1":"Manage them closely","R2":"Keep them satisfied","R3":"Keep them informed","R4":"Monitor them occasionally ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". Assume you are managing an international project. Your team is located in Atlanta, Georgia, US; Berlin, Germany;  and Melbourne, Australia. You and your sponsor are  located in Paris, France, and your customer is located  in Athens, Greece. Recognizing the different locations  of the stakeholders in your project in its initial stages, a  best practice to follow in terms of working toward project  success is to—","R1":"Determine who decides the project is a success","R2":"Aligning the personal inputs of different project participants with a vision focused on success","R3":"Establishing the project culture during the initiating stage of the project","R4":"Identifying basic cultural characteristics and selecting one to follow ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". Based on a recent quality audit of your project, your organization’s quality assurance department is supportive  of your approach as it notes the following   characteristics  of quality that are being followed consistency. They  include all of the follow EXCEPT—","R1":"Cost of quality","R2":"Customer satisfaction","R3":"Management responsibility","R4":"High-performing team ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":". The plan quality management process includes all the following techniques EXCEPT—","R1":"Benchmarking","R2":"Design of experiments","R3":"Process analysis","R4":"Control charts ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":". In order for a matrix organizational approach to be successful, the two-boss situation should be resolved.  To overcome the two-boss problem, it is important to—","R1":"Have the project manager and the functional manager","R2":"Prepare a responsibility chart to define responsibilities","R3":"Guarantee a balance of power between the functional manager and the project manager","R4":"Promote interface relationship management ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". An intentional activity to ensure future performance of project work is aligned with the project management  plan is—","R1":"Preventive action","R2":"Corrective action","R3":"Implemented change requests","R4":"Work performance information ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". Close procurements is a process that involves includes activities for administrative closure such as—","R1":"Customer acceptance and final payment","R2":"Audit project success or failure and archiving records","R3":"Final contractor payment and lessons learned","R4":"Transition of the final product and acceptance of deliverables ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":". Assume your project communication management plan has been approved by your sponsor and the members  of your Steering Committee. You are managing a global  project and have team members working virtually in  four continents and stakeholders in numerous locations.  Your next step is to—","R1":"Set up an information management system","R2":"Select communications technology","R3":"Determine performance reporting methods","R4":"Select a communications model ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":". Although your project team is working virtually, you are striving to make it a high-performing team. You held  a virtual kickoff meeting to ensure there was a shared  project vision. You now see that team members are  addressing the work to be done, but they do not seem to  be collaborating. You realize the team is—","R1":"Concerned about their formal roles and","R2":"Independent","R3":"Forming","R4":"Storming ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":". You are conducting a stakeholder analysis on your project . Your organization uses an approach to classify stakeholders based on their level of authority and their active  involvement in the project. This approach is known as—","R1":"A power/interest grid","R2":"A power/influence grid","R3":"An influence/impact grid","R4":"A salience model ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":". When managing projects, one important technique is capturing lessons learned from previous projects to  improve the organization’s project management process.  Therefore, in planning the project, it is important to plan  the closing procedures, particularly to review the—","R1":"Risk responses that were used","R2":"Checklists for risk identification","R3":"WBS and scope documents","R4":"Team members’ performance feedback ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":". One key interpersonal skill used to manage stakeholder expectations is—","R1":"Negotiation skills","R2":"Building trust","R3":"Compromise","R4":"Conversation ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":". A weighting system can be used for all but which one of the following reasons?","R1":"To select a single seller that will be asked to sign a","R2":"To establish a negotiating sequence by ranking all proposals by the weighted evaluation scores that have  been assigned","R3":"To quantify qualitative data to minimize possible bias","R4":"To establish minimum requirements of performance for one or more of the evaluation criteria ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":". One way to make it more likely practice project risk management on projects is to—","R1":"Hold meetings","R2":"Have the team take an orientation class on risk management early in the project","R3":"Give one team member the responsibility for risk management working in conjunction with the PMO","R4":"Assign each team member a risk to own, which is documented in the risk register ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". Your firm specializes in roller-coaster construction. It recently received an RFP to build the world’s most  \"death-defying\" roller coaster. You know that such  a roller coaster has never been built before and that  this would be a high-risk project. You are receiving a  cost-plus-award-fee contract, which means—","R1":"Your fee will be paid for completed work","R2":"Your fee amount will not change unless there is a scope change","R3":"Your fee is generally not subject to appeals","R4":"If your final cost is greater, you will share costs with the buyer based on a pre-negotiated cost  sharing formula ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":". Work performance information in control risks means that—","R1":"Recommended preventive or corrective action is","R2":"Outcomes of risk reassessments and risk audits are documented","R3":"Templates to the risk management plan and the risk register are recommended","R4":"A mechanism to communicate and support project decision making is provided ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":". A number of factors affect make-or-buy decisions such as—","R1":"Desired level of quality","R2":"Risk-related contract decisions","R3":"Value delivered by vendors meeting the needs","R4":"Performance data ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":". For complex procurement items, often contract negotiation can be an independent process. An example of an input if such a process is used is—","R1":"Open items list","R2":"Approved changes","R3":"Documented decisions","R4":"Expert judgment ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". One of the reasons why it is challenging to work on a virtual team is that e-mail is the primary form of communications. However, words alone typically comprise what  percent of the total impact of any message?","R1":"Seven percent","R2":"15 percent","R3":"38 percent","R4":"55 percent ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":". Assume you are working on a multi-phase project as your project is planned to last three years. A best practice  is to—","R1":"Periodically review the business case","R2":"Use a single prime contractor and have this contractor award any subcontracts","R3":"Rely on your PMO for guidance","R4":"Set up a ‘tight matrix’","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Lessons learned are best completed by?","R1":"The project manager.","R2":"The team","R3":"The sponsor.","R4":"The stakeholders  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Consideration of ongoing operations and maintenance is crucially important to products of projects. Ongoing operations and maintenance should:","R1":"Be included as activities to be performed during project closure.","R2":"Have a separate phase in the project life cycle, because a large portion of life cycle costs is devoted to maintenance and operations.","R3":"Not be viewed as part of a project.","R4":"Be viewed as a separate project.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The project team has just completed the initial project schedule and budget. The NEXT thing todo is to:","R1":"Identify risks.","R2":"Begin iterations.","R3":"Determine communications requirements.","R4":"Create a bar (Gantt) chart.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The project sponsor has just signed the project charter. What is the next thing to do?","R1":"Begin to complete the work packages","R2":"Validate scope.","R3":"Start integrated change control.","R4":"Start to create management plans.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The WBS and WBS dictionary are completed. The project team has begun working on identifying risks. The sponsor contacts the project manager, requesting that the responsibility assignment matrix be issued. The project has a budget of US $100,000 and is taking place in three countries using 14 human resources. There is little risk expected for the project, and the project manager has managed many projects similar to this one. What is the NEXT thing to do?","R1":"Understand the experience of the sponsor on similar projects.","R2":"Create an activity list.","R3":"Make sure the project scope is defined.","R4":"Complete risk management and issue the responsibility assignment matrix.  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"A project manager does not have much time to spend on planning before the mandatory start date arrives. He therefore wants to move through planning as effectively as possible. What advice would you offer?","R1":"Make sure you have a signed project charter and then start the WBS.","R2":"Create an activity list before creating a network diagram.","R3":"Document all the known risks before you document the high-level assumptions.","R4":"Finalize the quality management plan before you determine quality metrics.  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"During a team meeting, a team member asks about the measurements that will be used on the project to assess performance. The team member feels that some of the measures related to activities assigned to him are not valid measurements. The project is BEST considered to be in what part of the project management process?","R1":"Closing","R2":"Monitoring and controlling","R3":"Executing","R4":"Initiating  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The need for ________ is one major driving forces for communication in a project.","R1":"Optimization","R2":"Integrity","R3":"Integration","R4":"Differentiation  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"All of the following are parts of an effective change management plan EXCEPT:","R1":"Procedures.","R2":"Standards for reports.","R3":"Meetings.","R4":"Lessons learned.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"A work authorization system can be used to:","R1":"Manage who does each activity","R2":"Manage when and it what sequence work is done","R3":"Manage when each activity is done","R4":"Manage who does each activity and when it is done.    ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"A project is plagued by changes to the project charter. Who has the primary responsibility to decide if this changes are necessary?","R1":"The PM","R2":"The project team","R3":"The sponsor","R4":"The stakeholders  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Effective project integration usually requires an emphasis on:","R1":"The personal careers of the team members.","R2":"Timely updates to the project management plan.","R3":"Effective communication at key interface points.","R4":"Product control.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"You are taking over a project during project planning and discover that six individuals have signed the project charter. Which of the following should MOST concern you?","R1":"Who will be a member of the change control board","R2":"Spending more time on configuration management","R3":"Getting a single project sponsor","R4":"Determining the reporting structure  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"The project manager is working to clearly describe the level of involvement expected from everyone on the project in order to prevent rework, conflict, and coordination problems. Which of the following BEST describes the project managers efforts?","R1":"Develop Project Management Plan and Plan Quality Management","R2":"Manage Stakeholder Engagement and Direct and Manage Project Work","R3":"Validate Scope and Control Quality","R4":"Identify Risks and Develop Project Team  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"All of the following are parts of the Direct and Manage Project Work process EXCEPT:","R1":"Identifying changes.","R2":"Using a work breakdown structure.","R3":"Implementing corrective actions.","R4":"Setting up a project control system.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"A project manager is appointed to held a highly technical project in an area with which this person has limited familiarity. The project manager delegates the processes of Develop Schedule, Estimate Costs, Define Activities, and Estimate Activity Resources to various project team members, and basically serves as an occasional referee and coordinator of activities. The results of this approach are likely to be:","R1":"A team functioning throughout the project at a very high level, demonstrating creativity and commitment.","R2":"A team that initially experiences some amounts of confusion, but that after a period of time becomes a cohesive and effective unit.","R3":"A team that is not highly productive, but that stays together because of the work environment created by the project manager.","R4":"A team that is characterized by poor performance, low morale, high levels of conflict, and high turnover.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You are in the middle of executing a major modification to an existing product when you learn that the resources promised at the beginning of the project are not available. The BEST thing to do is to:","R1":"Show how the resources were originally promised to your project.","R2":"Replan the project without the resources.","R3":"Explain the impact if the promised resources are not made available.","R4":"Crash the project.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The primary customer of a project has requested an application change during user testing. As project manager, how should you BEST address this issue?","R1":"Develop a risk mitigation plan.","R2":"Create a formal change request.","R3":"Inform the project sponsor of changes to scope, cost, and schedule.","R4":"Ensure the scope change complies with all relevant contractual provisions.  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"The engineering department has uncovered a problem with the cost accounting system and has asked the systems department to analyze what is wrong and fix the problem. You are a project manager working with the cost accounting programs on another project. Management has issued a change request to the change control board to add the new work to your project. Your existing project has a cost performance index (CPI) of 1.2 and a schedule performance index (SPI) of 1.3, so you have some room to add work without delaying your existing project or going over budget. However, you cannot see how the new work fits within the project charter for your existing project. After some analysis, you determine that the new work and existing work do not overlap and can be done concurrently. They also require different skill sets. Which of the following is the BEST thing to do?","R1":"Develop a project charter.","R2":"Reestimate the project schedule with input from the engineering department.","R3":"Validate the scope of the new work with the help of the stakeholders.","R4":"Identify changes to the work.  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"The work breakdown structure can BEST be thought of as an effective aid for __ communications.","R1":"Team","R2":"Project manager","R3":"Customer","R4":"Stakeholder  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"You are managing a six-month project and have held bi-weekly meetings with your project stakeholders. After five-and-a-half months of work, the project is on schedule and budget, but the stakeholders are not satisfied with the deliverables. This situation will delay the project completion by one month. The MOST important process that could have prevented this situation is:","R1":"Monitor and Control Risks.","R2":"Control Schedule.","R3":"Define Scope.","R4":"Control Scope.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"A dependency requiring that design be completed before manufacturing can start is an example of a(n):","R1":"Discretionary dependency.","R2":"External dependency.","R3":"Mandatory dependency.","R4":"Scope dependency.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Which of the following is the BEST project management tool to use to determine the longest time the project will take?","R1":"Work breakdown structure","R2":"Network diagram","R3":"Bar chart","R4":"Project charter  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Your project management plan results in a project schedule that is too long. If the project network diagram cannot change but you have extra personnel resources, what is the BEST thing to do?","R1":"Fast track the project.","R2":"Level the resources.","R3":"Crash the project.","R4":"Perform Monte Carlo analysis.","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Which of the following is the BEST thing to do when asked to complete a project two days earlier than planned?","R1":"Tell senior management that the projects critical path does not allow the project to be finished earlier.","R2":"Tell your boss.","R3":"Meet with the team to look at options for crashing or fast tracking the critical path.","R4":"Work hard and see what the project status is next month.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"During project planning, you estimate the time needed for each activity and then add up the estimates to create the project estimate. You commit to completing the project by this date. What is wrong with this scenario?","R1":"The team did not create the estimate, and estimating takes too long using that method.","R2":"The team did not create the estimate, and a network diagram was not used.","R3":"The estimate is too long and should be created by management.","R4":"The project estimate should be the same as the customers required completion date.  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Based on the following, if you needed to shorten the duration of the project, which activity would you try to shorten?     ** Activity[Preceding Activity](Duration in Weeks): Start[None](0),A[Start](1),B[Start](2),C[Start](6),D[A](10),E[B,C](1),F[C](2),G[D](3),H[E](9),I[F](1),End[G,H,I](0)","R1":"Activity B","R2":"Activity D","R3":"Activity H","R4":"Activity C  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The WBS, estimates for each work package, and the network diagram are completed. The NEXT thing for the project manager to do is:","R1":"Sequence the activities.","R2":"Validate that they have the correct scope.","R3":"Create a preliminary schedule and get the teams approval.","R4":"Complete risk management  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"A new product development project has four levels in the work breakdown structure and has been sequenced using the PDM. The activity duration estimates have been received. What should be done next?","R1":"Create an activity list","R2":"Begin the WBS","R3":"Finalize the schedule","R4":"Compress the schedule.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Which of the following is a benefit of an analogous project estimate?","R1":"It will be closer to what the work will actually require.","R2":"It is based on a detailed understanding of what the work requires.","R3":"It gives the project team an understanding of managements expectations.","R4":"It helps the project manager determine if the project will meet the schedule.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The customer responsible for overseeing your project asks you to provide a written cost estimate that is 30 percent higher than your estimate of the projects cost. He explains that the budgeting process requires managers to estimate pessimistically to ensure enough money is allocated for projects. What is the BEST way to handle this?","R1":"Add the 30 percent as a lump sum contingency fund to handle project risks.","R2":"Add the 30 percent to your cost estimate by spreading it evenly across all project activities.","R3":"Create one cost baseline for budget allocation and a second one for the actual project management plan.","R4":"Ask for information on risks that would cause your estimate to be too low.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Analogous estimating:","R1":"Uses bottom-up estimating techniques.","R2":"Is used most frequently during project executing.","R3":"Uses top-down estimating techniques.","R4":"Calculates estimates using actual detailed historical costs.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"During which project management process group are budget forecasts created?","R1":"Monitoring and controlling","R2":"Planning","R3":"Initiating","R4":"Executing  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Your project has a medium amount of risk and is not very well defined. The sponsor hands you a project charter and asks you to confirm that the project can be completed within the project cost budget. What is the BEST method to handle this?","R1":"Build an estimate in the form of a range of possible results.","R2":"Ask the team members to help estimate the cost based on the project charter.","R3":"Based on the information you have, calculate a parametric estimate.","R4":"Provide an analogous estimate based on past history.  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"A manufacturing project has a schedule performance index (SPI) of 0.89 and a cost performance index (CPI) of 0.91. Generally, what is the BEST explanation for why this occurred?","R1":"The scope was changed.","R2":"A supplier went out of business and a new one needed to be found.","R3":"Additional equipment needed to be purchased.","R4":"A critical path activity took longer and needed more labor hours to complete.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Identified risks are:","R1":"An input to the Estimate Costs process.","R2":"An output of the Estimate Costs process.","R3":"Not related to the Estimate Costs process.","R4":"Both an input to and an output of the Estimate Costs process.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The difference between the cost baseline and the cost budget can be BEST described as:","R1":"The management reserves.","R2":"The contingency reserves.","R3":"The project cost estimate.","R4":"The cost account.  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Cost risk means:","R1":"There are risks that will cost the project money.","R2":"The project is too risky from a cost perspective.","R3":"There is a risk that project costs could go higher than planned.","R4":"There is a risk that the cost of the project will be lower than planned.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"A project manager has just taken over the project from another project manager during project executing. The previous project manager created a project budget, determined communications requirements, and went on to  complete work packages. What should the new project manager do NEXT?","R1":"Coordinate completion of work packages.","R2":"Identify quality standards.","R3":"Begin the Identify Risks process.","R4":"Execute the project management plan.  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Which of the following explains why quality is planned in and not inspected in?","R1":"It reduces quality and is less expensive.","R2":"It improves quality and is more expensive.","R3":"It reduces quality and is more expensive.","R4":"It improves quality and is less expensive.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The MOST common causes of conflict on a project are schedules, project priorities, and:","R1":"Personality.","R2":"Resources.","R3":"Cost.","R4":"Management  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You are a PM leading a cross functional project team in a weak matrix environment. None of your project team members report to you functionally and you do not have the ability to directly reward their performance. The project is difficult, involving tight date constraints and challenging quality standards. Which of the following types of project management power will likely be the MOST effective in this circumstance?","R1":"Referent","R2":"Expert","R3":"Penalty","R4":"Formal  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"A project has several teams. Team C has repeatedly missed deadlines in the past. This has caused team D to have to crash the critical path several times. As the team leader for team D, you should meet with:","R1":"The leader of team C.","R2":"The project manager.","R3":"The project manager and management.","R4":"The project manager and the leader of team C.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"A project is in the middle of the executing effort when a stakeholder suggests a major new change. This change will cause the third major overhaul of the project. At the same time, the project manager discovers that a major work package was not completed because a team members boss moved him to another project that had a higher priority. Which of the following is the BEST person for the project manager to address these issues with? ","R1":"The team","R2":"Senior management","R3":"The customer","R4":"The sponsor  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"A project manager had a complex problem to solve and facilitated a team decision about what needed to be done. A few months later, the problem resurfaced. What did the project manager MOST likely NOT do?","R1":"Perform proper risk analysis","R2":"Confirm the decision solved the problem","R3":"Have the project sponsor validate the decision","R4":"Use an Ishikawa diagram  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"The project manager is looking at the projects resource needs and lessons learned from past projects. This information causes the project manager to be concerned about the ability to acquire enough resources for the project in six months. Which of the following would be the LEAST effective preventive action?","R1":"Make sure functional managers have a copy of the resource histogram.","R2":"Show the sponsor the data, and explain the project managers concern.","R3":"Determine metrics to use as an early warning sign that resources will not be available.","R4":"Ask functional managers for their opinions.  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"A large project is underway when one of the team members reviews the project status report. He sees the project is currently running late. As he looks at the report further, he notices the delay will cause one of his activities to be scheduled during a time he will be out of the country and cannot work on the activity. This is of great concern to the team member because he is very committed to the success of the project and he does not want to be the cause of the project being further delayed. What is the BEST thing for him to do?","R1":"Contact the PM immediately to provide the PM with his schedule","R2":"Include the information in his next report","R3":"Request that the issue be added to the project issue log","R4":"Recommend preventive action  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Extensive use of __________ communication is most likely to aid in solving complex problems.","R1":"Formal verbal","R2":"Informal written","R3":"Formal written","R4":"Nonverbal  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"A project manager has a project team consisting of people in 4 different countries. The project is very important to the company, and the PM is concerned about his success. The length of the project schedule is acceptable. What type of communication should he use?","R1":"Informal verbal communication","R2":"Formal written communication","R3":"Formal verbal communication","R4":"Informal written communication  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"The project team meeting is not going well. Many attendees are talking at the same time, there are people who are not participating, and many topics are being discussed at random. Which of the following rules for effective meetings is NOT being adhered to?","R1":"Demonstrate courtesy and consideration of each other, and control who is allowed to speak.","R2":"Schedule meetings in advance.","R3":"Have a purpose for the meeting, with the right people in attendance.","R4":"Create and publish an agenda and a set of rules for controlling the meeting.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"A team member is visiting the manufacturing plant of one of the suppliers. Which of the following is the MOST important thing to be done in any telephone calls the project manager might make to the team member?","R1":"Ask the team member to repeat back what the project manager says.","R2":"Review the list of contact information for all stakeholders.","R3":"Ask the team member to look for change requests.","R4":"Review the upcoming meeting schedule.  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"A project manager has just been assigned a team that comes from many countries including Brazil, Japan, the United States, and Britain. What is her BEST tool for success?","R1":"The responsibility assignment matrix","R2":"The teleconference","R3":"Team communication with the WBS","R4":"Communication and well-developed people skills  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"All of the following are factors in the assessment of project risk EXCEPT:","R1":"Risk events.","R2":"Risk probability.","R3":"Amount at stake.","R4":"Insurance premiums.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"Which of the following risk events is MOST likely to interfere with attaining a projects schedule objective?","R1":"Delays in obtaining required approvals","R2":"Substantial increases in the cost of purchased materials","R3":"Contract disputes that generate claims for increased payments","R4":"Slippage of the planned post-implementation review meeting  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Risk tolerances are determined in order to help:","R1":"The team rank the project risks.","R2":"The project manager estimate the project.","R3":"The team schedule the project.","R4":"Management know how other managers will act on the project.  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"You are finding it difficult to evaluate the exact cost impacts of risks. You should evaluate on a (n):","R1":"Quantitative basis","R2":"Numerical basis","R3":"Qualitative basis","R4":"Econometric basis  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"A project manager has just finished the risk response plan for a US $387,000 engineering project. Which of the following should he probably do NEXT? ","R1":"Determine the overall risk rating of the project.","R2":"Begin to analyze the risks that show up in the project drawings.","R3":"Add work packages to the project work breakdown structure.","R4":"Hold a project risk reassessment.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Your team has come up with 434 risks and 16 major causes of those risks. The project is the last in a series of projects that the team has worked on together. The sponsor is very supportive, and a lot of time was invested in making sure the project work was complete and signed off by all key stakeholders. During project planning, the team cannot come up with an effective way to mitigate or insure against a risk. It is not work that can be outsourced, nor can it be deleted. What would be the BEST solution?","R1":"Accept the risk.","R2":"Continue to investigate ways to mitigate the risk.","R3":"Look for ways to avoid the risk.","R4":"Look for ways to transfer the risk.  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"You have been appointed as the manager of a new, large, and complex project. Because this project is business-critical and very visible, senior management has told you to analyze the project’s risks and prepare response strategies for them as soon as possible. The organization has risk management procedures that are seldom used or followed, and has had a history of handling risks badly. The project’s first milestone is in 2 weeks. In preparing the risk response plan, input from which of the following is generally LEAST important?","R1":"Project team members","R2":"Project sponsor.","R3":"Individuals responsible for risk management policies and templates","R4":"Key stakeholders  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"You were in the middle of a 2 year project to deploy new to field offices across the country. A hurricane caused power outages just when the upgrade was near completion. When the power was restored, all of the project reports and historical data were lost with no way of retrieving them. What should have been done to prevent this problem?","R1":"Purchase insurance.","R2":"Plan for a reserve fund.","R3":"Monitor the weather and have a contingency plan.","R4":"Schedule the installation outside of the hurricane season.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"A system development project is nearing project dosing when a previously unidentified risk is discovered. This could potentially affect the projects overall ability to deliver. What should be done NEXT?","R1":"Alert the project sponsor of potential impacts to cost, scope, or schedule.","R2":"Qualify the risk.","R3":"Mitigate this risk by developing a risk response plan.","R4":"Develop a workaround.  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"A watch list is an output of which risk management process?","R1":"Plan Risk Responses","R2":"Perform Quantitative Risk Analysis","R3":"Perform Qualitative Risk Analysis","R4":"Plan Risk Management  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"All the following statements about change control are incorrect EXCEPT:","R1":"A fixed-price contract will minimize the need for change control.","R2":"Changes seldom provide real benefits to the project.","R3":"Contracts should include procedures to accommodate changes.","R4":"More detailed specifications eliminate the causes of changes.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"A seller is working on a cost-reimbursable (CR) contract when the buyer decides he would like to expand the scope of services and change to a fixed-price (FP) contract. All of the following are the sellers options EXCEPT:","R1":"Completing the original work on a cost-reimbursable basis and then negotiating a fixed price for the additional work.","R2":"Completing the original work and rejecting the additional work.","R3":"Negotiating a fixed-price contract that includes the work.","R4":"Starting over with a new contract.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"All of the following MUST be present to have a contract EXCEPT:","R1":"A procurement statement of work.","R2":"Acceptance.","R3":"The address of the seller.","R4":"Buyers signatures.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"The sponsor is worried about the seller deriving extra profit on the cost plus fixed fee (CPFF) contract. Each month he requires the project manager to submit CPI calculations and an analysis of the cost to complete. The project manager explains to the sponsor that extra profits should NOT be a worry on this project because:","R1":"The team is making sure the seller does not cut scope.","R2":"All costs invoiced are being audited.","R3":"1bere can only be a maximum 10 percent increase if there is an unexpected cost overrun.","R4":"The fee is only received by the seller when the project is completed.  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"In a fixed-price (FP) contract, the fee or profit is:","R1":"Unknown.","R2":"Part of the negotiation involved in paying every invoice.","R3":"Applied as a line item to every invoice.","R4":"Determined with the other party at the end of the project.  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"A seller is awarded a contract to build a pipeline. The contract terms and conditions require a work plan to be issued for the buyers approval prior to commencing work but the seller fails to provide one. Which of the following is the BEST thing for the buyers project manager to do?","R1":"File a letter of intent.","R2":"Develop the work plan and issue it to the seller to move things along.","R3":"Issue a default letter.","R4":"Issue a stop work order to the seller until a work plan is prepared.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"Close Procurements is different from Close Project or Phase in that Close Procurements:","R1":"Occurs before Close Project or Phase.","R2":"Is the only one to involve the customer.","R3":"Includes the return of property.","R4":"May be done more than once for each contract.  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"Which of the following statements BEST describes how stakeholders are involved on a project?","R1":"They help to determine the project schedule, deliverables, and requirements.","R2":"They help to determine the project constraints and product deliverables.","R3":"They help to determine the resource needs and resource constraints on the project.","R4":"They approve the project charter, help provide assumptions, and create the project management plans  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"A project manager wants to more extensively involve the stakeholders on the project. Which of the following would be the BEST way to accomplish this?","R1":"Have the stakeholders periodically review the list of project requirements.","R2":"Invite the stakeholders to attend project status meetings.","R3":"Send status reports to the stakeholders.","R4":"Update the stakeholders on the status of all project changes.  ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"You are the PM for a large installation project when you realize there are over 200 potential stakeholders on the project. Which of the following would be the BEST course of action for you to take?","R1":"Eliminate some stakeholders","R2":"Find an effective way to gather the needs of all the stakeholders","R3":"Contact your manager, and ask which stakeholders are most important","R4":"Gather the needs of all the most influential stakeholders  ","Correct":"R2"},{"Question":"Information in the stakeholder register should be:","R1":"Accessible only to the project manager.","R2":"Available to the project manager and PMO staff.","R3":"Available to all stakeholders and team members.","R4":"Shared with others at the discretion of the project manager.  ","Correct":"R4"},{"Question":"The key objective of stakeholder management is:","R1":"Communication.","R2":"Coordination.","R3":"Satisfaction.","R4":"Relationships.  ","Correct":"R3"},{"Question":"A manager has responsibility for a project that has the support of a senior manager. From the beginning, you have disagreed with the manager as to how the project should proceed and what the deliverables should be. You and she have disagreed over many issues in the past. Your department has been tasked with providing some key work packages for the project. What should you do?","R1":"Provide the manager with what she needs.","R2":"Inform your manager of your concerns to get her support.","R3":"Sit down with the manager at the beginning of the project and attempt to describe why you object to the project, and discover a way to solve the problem.","R4":"Ask to be removed from the project. ","Correct":"R1"},{"Question":"A large, complex construction project in a foreign country requires coordination to move needed equipment through crowded city streets. To ensure the equipment is transported successfully, your contact in that country informs you that you will have to pay the local police a fee for coordinating traffic. What should you do?","R1":"Do not pay the fee because it is a bribe.","R2":"Eliminate the work","R3":"Pay the fine","R4":"Do not pay the fee if it is not part of the project estimate ","Correct":"R3"}]};